RUGIYYA MAMMADOV

Quincy, MA 02169

Phone: 617-708-4999 | Email: rugiyamammadova@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rugiyya-mammadova-8ab6088b/ | Github: https://github.com/Rugiyya | Portfolio: https://github.io/ProPortfolio/

SUMMARY

A dynamic, motivated, multilingual Web Developer with a 7-year background in Medicine and a certificate in Web Development from Harvard Extension School. Known for life-long dedication to learning, delivering excellent service in fast-paced environments, with the skill set to analyze complex information, and collaborate with diverse individuals. Fluent in English, Russian, Turkish, Azerbaijani.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Node.Js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, GIT, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, NoSQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX.

PROJECTS

BINDER | Front and Back End Developer | https://obscure-ridge-40329.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/Rugiyya/Binder

- Platform for students to share textbooks, notes and study material with other students.
- Tools used: Node.js, MySQL, Express.js, React/Redux, Bootstrap, Ant Design, Bcrypt, Moment

NFL GEAR ZONE | Front and Back End Developer | https://nflgearzone.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/Rugiyya/NFLGearZone/

- Monthly subscription app for a hat from favorite NFL team
- **Tools used**: Express.js, Node.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars, Moment, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

PICK YOUR TOMATOES | Front End Developer | https://yolk117.github.io/Pick-Your-Tomatoes/ | https://github.com/Rugiyya/Pick-Your-Tomatoes/

- App that allows users to pick the movie to watch my typing their favorite movies to a search box.
- Tools used: JavaScript, API's (OMDB, Taste Drive), Ajax, JSON, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

EXPERIENCE

Medical Assistant2018 – presentBeth Israel Deaconess Medical CenterNeedham, MA

- Record patient information such as vital signs, weight and change in medical history prior to each appointment
- Assisting physicians during performing procedure
- Execute quality assurance and control procedures to ensure compliance with HIPAA, CLIA, and OSHA.

Clinical Externship Tufts Medical Center

January 2017-February 2017 Boston, MA

- Garnered hands-on experience and proficiency in collecting vital signs/medical histories, preparing patients for examinations, conducting laboratory tests, processing laboratory specimens, drawing blood, performing electrocardiograms
- Coordinated administrative tasks such as reception, scheduling, insurance billing, and charting.

Physician Shafa Diagnostic Medical Center

May 2012 – May 2013

Baku, Azerbaijan

- Facilitated outpatient consultations to support for patients with/at risk of having genetic disorders.
- Performed genetic testing, PCR, and other procedures to inform medical diagnostics and treatment.

EDUCATION

Web Development Certificate, 2019

Harvard Extension School

Medical Assistant Certificate, Eligible for AMT RMA Certification, May 2016

Lincoln Tech - Allied Health Division - Somerville, MA

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Medicine, 2012

Medical University of Azerbaijan - Baku, Azerbaijan

Residency: 574 hours

Clerkships: Internal Medicine, Radial Diagnostic, General Surgery, Occupational Disease, Surgical Disease, Neurological Diseases, OB/GYN, Infectious Disease, Dermatology, Pediatrics, Ophthalmology, Otolaryngology, Genetics, Dietology.